Privacy Policy
==============

Who We Are and What This Policy Covers
--------------------------------------

This privacy statement (“Privacy Policy”) covers all websites (such as clustrmaps.com, ua.clustrmaps.com, ru.clustrmaps.com, etc) owned and operated by ClustrMaps (“ClustrMaps”, “we”, “us”, “our”) and all associated services, collectively referred to as “the Service”.

Below we explain how we collect, use, and share information about you, along with the choices that you have with respect to that information.

Information We Collect
----------------------

We only collect information about you if we have a reason to do so–for example, to provide our Services, to communicate with you, or to make our Services better.

We collect information in three ways: if and when you provide information to us, automatically through operating our Services, and from outside sources. Let’s go over the information that we collect.

### Information You Provide to Us

We collect information that you provide to us. The amount and type of information depends on the context and how we use the information. Here are some examples:

* _Basic Account Information:_ We ask for basic information from you in order to set up your account. For example, we require individuals who sign up for a ClustrMaps account to provide an email address–and that’s it.
* _Public Profile Information:_ If you have an account with us, we collect the information that you provide for your public profile.
* _Transaction and Billing Information:_ If you buy a subscription to a ClustrMaps plan, you will provide additional personal and payment information that is required to process the transaction and your payment, such as your name, credit card information, and contact information.
* _Content Information:_ Depending on the Services you use, you may also provide us with information about your site. This includes such information as your website’s address (URL), locations of recent visitors, and addresses of visited pages.
* _Communications With Us:_ You may also provide us information when you respond to surveys, communicate with our Support Team, or post a comment on our blog.

### Information We Collect Automatically

We also collect some information automatically:

* _Log Information_: Like most online service providers, we collect information that web browsers, mobile devices, and servers typically make available, such as the browser type, IP address, unique device identifiers, language preference, referring site, the date and time of access, operating system, and mobile network information.
* _Usage Information:_ We collect information about your usage of our Services. For example, we collect features enabled for your website or widget.
* _Location Information:_ We may determine the approximate location of your device from your IP address. We collect and use this information to, for example, calculate how many people visit our Services from certain geographic regions.
* _Information from Cookies & Other Technologies_: A cookie is a string of information that a website stores on a visitor’s computer, and that the visitor’s browser provides to the website each time the visitor returns. Pixel tags (also called web beacons) are small blocks of code placed on websites and emails. ClustrMaps uses cookies and other technologies like pixel tags to help us identify and track visitors, usage, and access preferences for our Services.

### Information We Collect from Other Sources

We may also get information about you from other sources. For example, if you create or log into your ClustrMaps account through another service (like Google or Facebook), we will receive information from that service (such as your username, basic profile information, and friends list) via the authorization procedures used by that service. The information we receive depends on which services you authorize and any options that are available.

How And Why We Use Information
------------------------------

### Purposes for Using Information

We use information about you as mentioned above and for the purposes listed below:

* To provide our Services–for example, to set up and maintain your account, host your website stats, backup and restore your stats, or charge you for any of our paid Services;
* To further develop and improve our Services–for example by adding new features that we think our users will enjoy or will help them to create and manage their websites more efficiently;
* To monitor and analyze trends and better understand how users interact with our Services, which helps us improve our Services and make them easier to use;
* To measure, gauge, and improve the effectiveness of our advertising, and better understand user retention and attrition–for example, we may analyze how many individuals purchased a plan after receiving a marketing message or the features used by those who continue to use our Services after a certain length of time;
* To monitor and prevent any problems with our Services, protect the security of our Services, detect and prevent fraudulent transactions and other illegal activities, and protect the rights and property of ClustrMaps and others, which may result in us declining a transaction or the use of our Services;
* To communicate with you, for example through an email, about offers and promotions offered by ClustrMaps and others we think will be of interest to you, solicit your feedback, or keep you up to date on ClustrMaps and our products; and
* To personalize your experience using our Services, target our marketing messages to groups of our users (for example, those who have a particular plan with us or have been our user for a certain length of time), and serve relevant advertisements.

### Legal Bases for Collecting and Using Information

A note here for those in the European Union about our legal grounds for processing information about you under EU data protection laws, which is that our use of your information is based on the grounds that:

(1) The use is necessary in order to fulfill our commitments to you under our Terms of Service or other agreements with you or is necessary to administer your account–for example, in order to enable access to our website on your device or charge you for a paid plan; or

(2) The use is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation; or

(3) The use is necessary in order to protect your vital interests or those of another person; or

(4) We have a legitimate interest in using your information–for example, to provide and update our Services, to improve our Services so that we can offer you an even better user experience, to safeguard our Services, to communicate with you, to measure, gauge, and improve the effectiveness of our advertising, and better understand user retention and attrition, to monitor and prevent any problems with our Services, and to personalize your experience; or

(5) You have given us your consent–for example before we place certain cookies on your device and access and analyze them later on, as described in our [Cookie Policy](https://clustrmaps.com/cookies).

Sharing Information
-------------------

### How We Share Information

We do not sell our users’ private personal information.

We share information about you in the limited circumstances spelled out below and with appropriate safeguards on your privacy:

* _Subsidiaries, Employees, and Independent Contractors:_ We may disclose information about you to our subsidiaries, our employees, and individuals who are our independent contractors that need to know the information in order to help us provide our Services or to process the information on our behalf. We require our subsidiaries, employees, and independent contractors to follow this Privacy Policy for personal information that we share with them.
* _Third Party Vendors:_ We may share information about you with third party vendors who need to know information about you in order to provide their services to us, or to provide their services to you or your site. This group includes vendors that help us provide our Services to you (like payment providers that process your credit and debit card information, fraud prevention services that allow us to analyze fraudulent payment transactions, postal and email delivery services that help us stay in touch with you, customer chat and email support services that help us communicate with you), those that assist us with our marketing efforts (e.g. by providing tools for identifying a specific marketing target group or improving our marketing campaigns), those that help us understand and enhance our Services (like analytics providers). We require vendors to agree to privacy commitments in order to share information with them. Other vendors are listed in our more specific policies (e.g. our Cookie Policy).
* _Legal Requests:_ We may disclose information about you in response to a subpoena, court order, or other governmental request.
* _To Protect Rights, Property, and Others:_ We may disclose information about you when we believe in good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect the property or rights of ClustrMaps, third parties, or the public at large.
* _Business Transfers:_ In connection with any merger, sale of company assets, or acquisition of all or a portion of our business by another company, or in the unlikely event that ClustrMaps goes out of business or enters bankruptcy, user information would likely be one of the assets that is transferred or acquired by a third party. If any of these events were to happen, this Privacy Policy would continue to apply to your information and the party receiving your information may continue to use your information, but only consistent with this Privacy Policy.
* _With Your Consent:_ We may share and disclose information with your consent or at your direction. For example, we may share your information with third parties with which you authorize us to do so, such as the social media services.
* _Aggregated or De-Identified Information:_ We may share information that has been aggregated or reasonably de-identified, so that the information could not reasonably be used to identify you. For instance, we may publish aggregate statistics about the use of our Services
* Published Support Requests: And if you send us a request (for example, via a support email or one of our feedback mechanisms), we reserve the right to publish that request in order to help us clarify or respond to your request or to help us support other users.

### Information Shared Publicly

Information that you choose to make public is disclosed publicly.

Websites’ stats pages are public by default.

Public information may also be indexed by search engines or used by third parties.

How Long We Keep Information
----------------------------

ClustrMaps will retain your personal information for as long as your account is active or as required to comply with applicable laws and to establish, exercise or defend our legal rights.

Security
--------

Your account information is password-protected. We recommend that you choose a strong and secure password.

While no online service is 100% secure, we work very hard to protect information about you against unauthorized access, use, alteration, or destruction, and take reasonable measures to do so, such as monitoring our Services for potential vulnerabilities and attacks. If we learn of a system security breach, we will notify you electronically so you can take appropriate steps to protect yourself.

Choices
-------

You have several choices available when it comes to information about you:

* _Limit the Information that You Provide:_ If you have an account with us, you can choose not to provide the optional account information, profile information, and transaction and billing information. Please keep in mind that if you do not provide this information, certain features of our Services–for example, hidden counter, advanced backlinks–may not be accessible.
* _Opt-Out of Electronic Communications:_ You may opt out of receiving promotional messages from us. Just follow the instructions in those messages. If you opt out of promotional messages, we may still send you other messages, like those about your account and legal notices.
* _Set Your Browser to Reject Cookies:_ At this time, ClustrMaps does not respond to “do not track” signals across all of our Services. However, you can usually choose to set your browser to remove or reject browser cookies before using ClustrMaps website, with the drawback that certain features of ClustrMaps’ websites may not function properly without the aid of cookies.
* _Close Your Account:_ While we’d be very sad to see you go, if you no longer want to use our Services, you can [close your ClustrMaps account](https://clustrmaps.com/profile/account). Please keep in mind that we may continue to retain your information after closing your account–for example, when that information is reasonably needed to comply with (or demonstrate our compliance with) legal obligations such as law enforcement requests, or reasonably needed for our legitimate business interests.

Your Rights
-----------

If you are located in certain countries, including those that fall under the scope of the European General Data Protection Regulation (AKA the “GDPR”), data protection laws give you rights with respect to your personal data, subject to any exemptions provided by the law, including the rights to:

* Request access to your personal data;
* Request correction or deletion of your personal data;
* Object to our use and processing of your personal data;
* Request that we limit our use and processing of your personal data; and
* Request portability of your personal data.

You can usually access, correct, or delete your personal data using your account settings and tools that we offer, but if you aren’t able to do that, or you would like to contact us about one of the other rights, scroll down to How to Reach Us to, well, find out how to reach us.

EU individuals also have the right to make a complaint to a government supervisory authority.

Other Things You Should Know (Keep Reading!)
--------------------------------------------

### Transferring Information

Because ClustrMaps’ Services are offered worldwide, the information about you that we process when you use the Services in the EU may be used, stored, and/or accessed by individuals operating outside the European Economic Area (EEA) who work for us, other members of our group of companies, or third party data processors. This is required for the purposes listed in the How and Why We Use Information section above. When providing information about you to entities outside the EEA, we will take appropriate measures to ensure that the recipient protects your personal information adequately in accordance with this Privacy Policy as required by applicable law.

### Ads and Analytics Services Provided by Others

Ads appearing on any of our Services may be delivered by advertising networks. Other parties may also provide analytics services via our Services. These ad networks and analytics providers may set tracking technologies (like cookies) to collect information about your use of our Services and across other websites and online services. These technologies allow these third parties to recognize your device to compile information about you or others who use your device. This information allows us and other companies to, among other things, analyze and track usage, determine the popularity of certain content, and deliver advertisements that may be more targeted to your interests. Please note this Privacy Policy only covers the collection of information by ClustrMaps and does not cover the collection of information by any third party advertisers or analytics providers.

### Privacy Notice for Visitors to Our Users’ Sites

Our users (for example, website owners, or webmasters) may install our stats widgets (such as the Map Widget or Rotating Globe Widget) on their websites. On behalf of our users and in accordance with our user agreement, we may also process information about visitors to our users’ websites. _Our Users are responsible for publishing privacy policies on their websites that explain how data about visitors is collected via the widgets. The policy should also explain how that information is used and disclosed._.

By installing a ClustrMaps widget you agree to obtain your visitors’ legally valid consent to the use of cookies and sharing, and the use of personal information. Our users must retain records of consent given by their visitors and provide clear instructions for revocation of consent. Failing to meet these requirement may result in account termination

We collect the following information about visitors to our Users’ websites:

* Technical Data: We collect the information that web browsers, mobile devices, and servers typically make available about visitors to a Site, such as the IP address, browser type, referring site, the date and time of access, operating system.
* Location Information: We may determine the approximate location of a visitor’s device from the IP address. We collect and use this information to, for example, tally for our Users how many people visit their Sites from certain geographic regions, or show visitors’ locations on the map.
* Viewed Pages: We may collect the information about pages viewed by visitors to our Users’ sites.

Privacy Policy Changes
----------------------

Although most changes are likely to be minor, ClustrMaps may change its Privacy Policy from time to time. ClustrMaps encourages visitors to frequently check this page for any changes to its Privacy Policy. If we make changes, we will notify you by providing a notice (such as adding a statement to our homepage or sending you a notification through e-mail or your dashboard). If you have a ClustrMaps account, you should also check your dashboard for alerts to these changes. Your continued use of the Services after any change in this Privacy Policy will constitute your consent to such change.

How to Reach Us
---------------

If you have a question about this Privacy Policy, or you would like to contact us about any of the rights mentioned in the Your Rights section above, please contact us using [the following form](https://clustrmaps.com/contacts) or [\[email protected\]](https://clustrmaps.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

ClustrMaps.com

ClustrMaps.com aggregates public records to analyze the US cities, their social demography, and business environment. We cannot guarantee the accuracy, correctness and/or timeliness of the data. Therefore, ClustrMaps.com cannot be used for any purpose covered by the [FCRA](https://www.ftc.gov/legal-library/browse/statutes/fair-credit-reporting-act)

About

Legal

Widget

 © ClustrMaps.com
